Sanghyun Son, PhD

Contact Information

Affiliation: Samsung Electronics

Address: 130 Samsung-ro, Yeongtong-gu, Suwon-si, Gyeonggi-do, 16678, Korea

Email: sonsang35(at)gmail.com

Github/Homepage: https://github.com/sanghyun-son, https://sanghyun-son.github.io

Google scholar: link

Personal Statement

I earned my Ph.D. in Electrical and Computer Engineering from Seoul National University. My research has focused on deep learning and low-level image restoration, particularly image super-resolution with an emphasis on enhancing the visual quality of in-the-wild images.

Currently, I am with the AI Center at Samsung Electronics. I have been fascinated by the immense potential of large language models (LLMs) and am actively exploring their applications, particularly on manufacturing process optimization using large-scale in-house datasets.

Outside of my primary research, I have a strong passion for analyzing open-source libraries and frameworks and understanding how complex systems operate efficiently at scale. I also enjoy developing side projects that integrate AI into everyday life. One such project I am particularly proud of is a fully automated Discord bot that summarizes daily voice chats among my friends.

Work Experience

Staff Research Engineer at Samsung Electronics Core Algorithm Lab, AI Development, AI Center

Dec. 2024 - Present

(Dec. 2024 – Present) LRM and Agentic Workflow for Manufacturing Process Automation

- Implemented a distributed RL system (>128 GPUs) for training in-house reasoning models.
- Tech Stack: Ray, FSDP, vLLM, SGLang

Computer Vision TU, AI Research Center, SAIT

Sep. 2023 – Nov. 2024

(Aug. 2024 – Dec. 2024) LLM-based Safeguard System for in-house AI Models.

- Led model orchestration and supervised fine-tuning for in-house LLM infrastructure.
- Organized a development team of ~ 10 researchers and engineers for in-house model development.
- Officially released a Korean-specialized safety model for internal systems.
- Tech Stack: FastAPI, vLLM, Transformers, DeepSpeed

(Apr. 2024 - Nov. 2024) Domain-Specific LLMs for Manufacturing Process Automation.

- Fine-tuned domain-specific LLMs using in-house data and achieved $\sim 10x$ speedup compared to the larger general-purpose model.
- Partnered with manufacturing engineers to deliver the best user experience.
- Officially released the domain-specific model for internal engineers.
- Led a TF team of 7 researchers for multi-modal data curation.
- Tech Stack: vLLM, Transformers, DeepSpeed, Whisper

(Sep. 2023 – Mar. 2024) AI-based ISP Solution for Low-light Environments.

- Led a team of 3 researchers and developed low-light machine vision systems for automotive.
- Tech Stack: Hardware ISP, PyTorch

Internship

Student Research Intern Jan. 2019 - Jun. 2019

Research Topic: Real-World Single Image Super-Resolution

Google Cloud, Sunnyvale, CA, USA

Mentor: Ming-Hsuan Yang

Education

Ph.D. in Department of ECE

Mar. 2017 – Aug. 2023

Integrated Ph.D. program in Seoul National University (SNU), Seoul, Korea Thesis: Generalized Resampling Model for Practical Image Super-Resolution

Advisor: Kyoung Mu Lee

B.S. in Department of ECE, $Summa\ Cum\ Laude\ (Rank: 9/174)$

Mar. 2013 - Feb. 2017

Seoul National University (SNU), Seoul, Korea

International Publications (Selected)

- Bee Lim, Sanghyun Son, Heewon Kim, Seungjun Nah, and Kyoung Mu Lee, "Enhanced Deep Residual Networks for Single Image Super-Resolution," NTIRE 2017 workshop in conjunction with CVPR, 2017. (Challenge winners, Workshop best paper, Over 8,000 citations on Google Scholar, over 2,500 Github stars)
- Reyhaneh Neshatavar*, Mohsen Yavartanoo*, **Sanghyun Son**, and Kyoung Mu Lee, "ICF-SRSR: Invertible scale-Conditional Function for Self-Supervised Real-world Single Image Super-Resolution," In **WACV**, 2024.
- Joonkyu Park, **Sanghyun Son**, and Kyoung Mu Lee, "Content-Aware Local GAN for Photo-Realistic Super-Resolution," In **ICCV**, 2023.
- Wooseok Lee, **Sanghyun Son**, and Kyoung Mu Lee, "AP-BSN: Self-Supervised Denoising for Real-World Images via Asymmetric PD and Blind-Spot Network," In **CVPR**, 2022.
- Seungjun Nah, **Sanghyun Son**, Jaerin Lee, and Kyoung Mu Lee, "Clean Images are Hard to Reblur: Exploiting the Ill-Posed Inverse Task for Dynamic Scene Deblurring," In **ICLR**, 2022.
- Geonwoon Jang, Wooseok Lee, **Sanghyun Son**, and Kyoung Mu Lee, "C2N: Practical Generative Noise Modeling for Real-World Denoising," In **ICCV**, 2021.
- Sanghyun Son and Kyoung Mu Lee, "SRWarp: Generalized Image Super-Resolution under Arbitrary Transformation," In CVPR, 2021.
- Sanghyun Son, Jaeha Kim, Wei-Sheng Lai, Ming-Hsuan Yang, and Kyoung Mu Lee, "Toward Real-World Super-Resolution via Adaptive Downsampling Models,' IEEE Trans. on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (**TPAMI**), vol. 44, no. 11, pp. 8567-8670, 2022. https://doi.org/10.1109/TPAMI.2021.3106790
- Sanghyun Son and Kyoung Mu Lee, "Image Super-Resolution," in Ikeuchi K. (eds) Computer Vision. Springer, Cham, 2021. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-03243-2_838-1
- Seungjun Nah, **Sanghyun Son**, and Kyoung Mu Lee, "Recurrent Neural Networks with Intra-Frame Iterations for Video Deblurring," In **CVPR**, 2019.
- Sanghyun Son, Seungjun Nah, and Kyoung Mu Lee, "Clustering Convolutional Kernels to Compress Deep Neural Networks," In ECCV, 2018.

International Collaborations and Reports (Selected)

- Sanghyun Son, Suyoung Lee, Seungjun Nah, Radu Timofte, and Kyoung Mu Lee, "NTIRE 2021 Challenge on Video Super-Resolution," NTIRE 2021 workshop in conjunction with CVPR, 2021.
- Sanghyun Son, Jaerin Lee, Seungjun Nah, Radu Timofte, and Kyoung Mu Lee, "AIM 2020 Challenge on Video Temporal Super-Resolution," **AIM 2020** workshop in conjunction with **ICCV**, 2020.
- Seungjun Nah, **Sanghyun Son**, Radu Timofte, and Kyoung Mu Lee, "NTIRE 2020 Challenge on Image and Video Deblurring," **NTIRE 2020** workshop in conjunction with **CVPR**, 2020.
- Seungjun Nah, **Sanghyun Son**, Radu Timofte, and Kyoung Mu Lee, "AIM 2019 Challenge on Video Temporal Super-Resolution: Methods and Results," **AIM 2019** workshop in conjunction with **ICCV**, 2019.
- Seungjun Nah, Sungyong Baik, Seokil Hong, Gyeongsik Moon, **Sanghyun Son**, Radu Timofte, and Kyoung Mu Lee, "NTIRE 2019 Challenge on Video Deblurring and Super-Resolution: Dataset and Study," **NTIRE 2019** workshop in conjunction with **CVPR**, 2019.

Academic Experience & Service

Workshop Challenge Co-organizer	
NTIRE 2021 Challenge on Video Super-Resolution, Video Deblurring NTIRE 2021 workshop in conjunction with CVPR, 2021	Jun. 2021
AIM 2020 Challenge on Video Temporal Super-Resolution AIM 2020 workshop in conjunction with ECCV, 2020	Aug. 2020

AIM 2019 Challenge on Video Temporal Super-Resolution AIM 2019 workshop in conjunction with ICCV, 2019

Sep. 2019

Conference Reviewer

CVPR, ECCV, ICCV, and the corresponding Workshops on Image Restoration

Journal Reviewer

IEEE TPAMI, TIP, TCI Springer IJCV Elsevier CVIU

Teaching Assistant

EE729.003: Advanced Trends in Computer Vision (ATCV) Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea	Sep. 2020 – Dec. 2020
Neural Processing Expert (NPEX): Image Restoration Lab. Samsung Electronics SNU R&D Center, Seoul, Korea	Sep. 2020
EE729.001: Topics in Control and Automation Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea	Sep. 2019 – Dec. 2019
Neural Processing Expert (NPEX): Image Restoration Lab. Samsung Electronics SNU R&D Center, Seoul, Korea	Jul. 2019
EE306: Signal and Systems Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea	Mar. 2017 – Jun. 2017

Research Projects

MLPerf Mobile AI Benchmark: Super-Resolution Track

Apr. 2022 – Mar. 2023

in conjunction with MLCommons

Invited talk: Mobile Super-Resolution on the MLPerf App - Benchmarking and Challenges Efficient Deep Learning Workshop for Computer Vision, in conjunction with **CVPR**, 2023.

Pixel-wise Adaptive Weighting for Perceptual Image Super-Resolution

May 2022 - May 2023

with Naver

Efficient Vision Transformer for Image Super-Resolution

May 2021 - May 2022

with Naver

Raw Food Image Generation by Domain Adaptation with Samsung Research

Dec. 2020 – Dec. 2021

Awards and Honors

- The Best Collaboration Award from the AI Research Center, Samsung Electronics, 2024.
- The KCCV Sang-Uk Lee Prize (Test of Time award) from KCCV 2022.
- Winner of Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship Korea 2021.
- Highly Cited Paper Award from Department of ECE, SNU, 2018.
- 1st Place Award in NTIRE 2017 Challenge on Single Image Super-Resolution.
- Best Paper Award of NTIRE 2017 Workshop: Challenge Track.

Scholarships

• Youlchon AI Stars Scholarship, Youlchon Foundation	2022
• Kwanjeong Scholarship, Kwanjeong Educational Foundation	2017 - 2018
• National Scholarship for Science & Engineering, Korea Student Aid Foundation	2015 - 2016
• Scholarship of Academic Excellence, Seoul National University	2013 - 2014

Skills

• Programming languages

Expert: Python

Intermediate: C++, MATLAB

Novice: CUDA (can write a custom kernel), Javascript (especially for my side projects)

• Software stacks (selected)

General Deep Learning: PyTorch (8+ years of experience), TensorFlow (mobile deployment)

Distributed Computing: DeepSpeed, FSDP (distributed training with >128 GPUs) **Applications:** FastAPI (especially for my side projects), LangChain, vLLM, SGLang

• Others: Korean (Native), English (Working proficiency), Japanese (Novice), LATEX

References

Advisor Kyoung Mu Lee

Professor

Seoul National University kyoungmu(at)snu.ac.kr

https://cv.snu.ac.kr/index.php/kmlee

Mentor Ming-Hsuan Yang

Professor

UC Merced, Google mhyang(at)ucmerced.edu

http://faculty.ucmerced.edu/mhyang